What are the biggest differences between
men getting on TRT when they're very
young, relatively 30, 35, uh, in
comparison to when they are a bit older,
45, 50 or over? Are there any
differences? And if so, what are they?
Yeah. Uh, it it's common to see both of
these age groups. uh we see everyone
from very young fairly young ages um
even in their 20s um all the way up to
people who are in their 80s still
wanting to optimize their health. So um
it's not uncommon that I I see you know
a patient in room one that's 30 years
old and a guy in room two that's 60 year
years old and when you look at their lab
results and you don't know which one's
which they look almost identical. So the
first thing I would say is there's a lot
of similarities between the two. They
oftent times have the same severity of
their symptoms and they have the same
severity of hypogonatism in their lab
results. Um the differences between the
two is that when you give a 30-year-old
testosterone, he might improve a little
bit faster because he might not have as
many complicated um um other medical
issues going on at the same time. Um he
might not have as much polyarm pharmacy
going on, although that's not always
true. We have a lot of young guys being
put on a lot of medications early on too
now um that complicate things. But I do
sometimes see those 30-year-olds improve
a little quicker right out the gate with
just testosterone versus the 60-year-old
um oftentimes needs other hormonal
support and consideration of other
issues like um microvascular damage. um
if their main concern is erectile
dysfunction or um even endurance and
cardiovascular health. Yeah. What I've
learned through the years doing these
videos from Dave Lee and as from Dr.
Keith Nichols is that um men that are a
little bit older 45 50 um they they
might all need optimization of all the
hormones at once pregnolone, DHEA,
meatonin and so on. while the younger
guys can start out with just
testosterone and they won't probably
need the DHEM pregnone. Is that also
your experience? Yeah. Yeah, I agree
with that. And then also mentioning
thyroid in there as a another thing to
look at and consider as part of the
whole picture. Um but thyroid is one
that some younger guys do need as well.
And um you know even though some younger
guys don't need DHEA and pregnant alone,
there oftentimes are still some issues
there with younger guys too, especially
I see with shift workers um and um like
veterans too. Um but I I do agree that
usually it's the older guys that you
have to look at starting all of those
things at once. Um, you know, some other
differences would be, you know, the
younger guys are more prone to side
effects like acne. I don't oftentimes
have six-year-olds experience acne on
testosterone, but the 30-year-old
usually has at least a little bit, if
not um, more moderate amounts, which I'm
sure you have a lot of experiencing,
too.